Gabriel De Almeida

Machello@gabrieldealmeida.com Regabrieldealmeida.com Regabedealmeida Peach, FLest Palm Beach, Flest P

Summary

I'm a software engineer based in West Palm Beach, FL. I'm the co-creator of Campion ☑, an edge-based serverless middleware for implementing circuit-breaking functionality for distributed services. I've worked with multiple technologies across the entire stack and consider myself language and framework agnostic. Previously, I founded BooklyBox, which was successfully acquired by Quarterly ☑.

Skills

Backend Node.js, Express, Ruby, Rails, Sinatra, PostgreSQL,

MongoDB, RESTful APIs

Frontend

JavaScript (ES6). React/Redux, HTML/CSS, TailwindCSS, jQuery

Tooling

Git/GitHub, Docker, Linux

Cloud

AWS, Cloudflare, Digital Ocean, Heroku

Professional Experience

2020 - present

Co-Creator, Software Engineer, Campion — campion-breaker.github.io ☑

- Co-created Campion, an edge-based serverless middleware for implementing circuitbreaking functionality for synchronously called distributed services
- Built Campion to work on AWS (IAM, CloudFront, Lambda, and DynamoDB) and Cloudflare (Workers and Workers KV) with a single CLI command
- Designed Campion to work with all HTTP methods and to forward any incoming and outgoing headers and body
- Resolved race conditions when incrementing failure/success counts by appending new entries to databases with unique time-based keys
- Load tested Campion by using artillery.io to simulate 5,000+ concurrent requests
- Built easy-to-use CLI that abstracts away complex deployment logic and a beautiful dashboard for users to track their metrics with Node.js, Express, React, and Redux
- Collaborated daily with a fully remote team of engineers
- Co-authored Campion's case study: https://campion-breaker.github.io ☑

2019 - present

Software Engineer, Self Employed

- Dayllo: Trello-like app with React/Redux front-end and Ruby on Rails REST API backend
- Airline Routes: an interactive SVG map for viewing and filtering airline routes built with React and bootstrapped with Create React App
- Team Tickets: Ticket tracking app written in Ruby/Rails 6, PostgresSQL, deployed on Heroku

2017 - 2018

Co-Founder, Growth Director, PageHabit (Quarterly Subsidiary)

- Led the growth team and grew our online book community to over 50,000 active members
- Created the influencer program and the wildly popular PH contests to drive sustainable growth

2015 - 2017

Founder, BooklyBox

- Founded BooklyBox, a monthly book membership with a thriving online community consisting of thousands of members
- Led a team of four employees and 15 moderators for our online community
- Acquired by Quarterly

 in May of 2017

Education